<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/moodle-quiz.xsd">
    <description>Overview of NoSQL concepts</description>
    <question type="truefalse">
        <questiontext>
            <text>Relational databases were originally designed to leverage distributed computing architectures</text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>false</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>Most relational database systems were designed around single CPU mainframe and minicomputer systems.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question type="truefalse">
        <category>
            <text>
            </text>
        </category>
        <questiontext>
            <text>Key-values stores are searchable by the data within the value portion of a key-value pair.</text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>false</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>You can only lookup items in a key-value store based on the data within a key.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question type="multichoice">
        <questiontext>
            <text>Which of the following are considered NoSQL database architectural patterns:<br/>
                a) binary trees<br/>
                b) hash-tables<br/>
                c) graph stores<br/>
                d) object-oriented databases<br/>
            </text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>b</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>The four new architectures are key-values stores, column-family stores, graph stores and document stores.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question type="multichoice">
        <questiontext>
            <text>An XML database is considered what type of NoSQL database pattern:<br/>
                a) key-value store<br/>
                b) column-family store<br/>
                c) graph stores<br/>
                d) document store<br/>
            </text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>d</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>XML databases hold hierarchical documents where all elements and attributes can be queried.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question type="multichoice">
        <questiontext>
            <text>Which of the following patterns is used in distributed computing.
            a) move data to the queries
            b) move queries to the data
            </text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>a</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>Queries are generally much smaller than data so it is usually much more efficient to move
                queries to the data.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question type="multichoice">
        <questiontext>
            <text>Which of the following best describes the use of consistent hashing
                a) a way to assign a data element to a node in a cluster<br/>
                b) a way to encrypt data to prevent unauthorized access<br/>
                c) a way to lookup joins when tables are on different nodes
                d) a way to keep data consistent within a table
            </text>
        </questiontext>
        <answer>
            <text>a</text>
            <feedback>
                <text>Consistent hashing allows any node in a cluster to determine what node a data item is located.</text>
            </feedback>
        </answer>
    </question>
</quiz>